a database name my app username my user and database users my and capital you capital
p capital my user pass one two three my user pass one two three okay so we now
okay to say this is our database name and database user and password and
so here if you want to fix the permission it is also very important we
need to do that this step but since we are in a production environment or we do
only local local it's local development or for our for a sake of our
tutorial we will give read write execute for users groups and others okay so
that the WordPress content is this is easiest way so that our Apache PHP
service in the container can execute the files that resize in Wp dash
content so we need to type these commands
okay and this is an importance very important step actually before we install
the WordPress from the local host we need to make sure that the connection that
Apache container we use to connect to my SQL container we need to have
some SQL extensions which is the POD and another one which is called my SQL
I and both of them unfortunately is not we will not find it in our downloaded
image from the Docker Hub so to override to overcome this issue we need
first to call this of this version of DevOps HP Apache and just to prove to
prove my point if we want to validate let's go to the Docker let's go to this
one and if I want to check if I have SQL I and PDO my SQL also GD
especially first two are very important my SQL I and PDO my SQL if I want to
find them here the comment didn't return anything and when you don't have SQL
extension you will get an error and we will not be able to install the WordPress
so you need to solve that by downloading a newer image and the newer image you
will stop the old one and remove it and then you will run the used version
after you download it so let's download it let's go out from the Docker let's
download it okay I have paused the video tell the Docker is downloaded and
pulled and now we have pulled from the Docker Hub the web DevOps Apache 8.2
okay this is very good so now if we just want to make my SQL extension
working we need to first stock my Apache my PHP - Apache okay and then we will
remove okay now we will run again the my - PHP - Apache but about this time
we will do everything the same the same networking that is shared with my
SQL and same ports of HTTP and HTTPS and the same mounting volume and we will
mounting to the destination of home and no more www will be mapped to - app and this
time we will use web that ops image okay so let's do it okay perfect and now
just verification for the extension my SQL or SK all SQL I extensions are
okay to verify it will enter to the Docker again okay and then we will type
the grep comment again if well now we have the GD my SQL ID O my zip then we
are and just to make sure that everything is okay if you want I actually don't
recall the comment if you want to make sure that everything is okay you can type
the comment of Docker ps - e just to view all of the container but when the one
that might call the problem was my SQL and if you want to make sure that if you
have any problem when your database is stuck or anything you need to reduce a
previous recording to see how we can use the container to see if my SQL is
container may stop for any reason so that you need to be aware that maybe it's
mapped to not mapped to the bar lived directory maybe either it is run with
some syntax error okay to skip certificate or something okay that's it but when
you run it and the PHP - Apache you will not have any any kind of these
problem to check no worries about this kind of problem so here let's go now we
are ready to install the WordPress which should be okay to install the WordPress
so to install the WordPress we just go to our browser
okay HTTP local rows okay it's gave me error database installed the
database connection I need to review the configuration file and then I will
come back to you okay I have found here important points that I have missed
actually that we defined the database users and password but we forgot to define
my -my SQL before we forgot to define the host -my SQL which in which the Apache
will connect to okay so we need to save the changes okay so here the database
name I have my user and we have the database host so we are okay now and for the
comment for the Docker I have remembered the Docker PS -A but the thing here
that you need to take care not to run it inside a Docker I should run it
inside the host itself so here if we connect day now we will install the WordPress
we select English and here let's type sites default or let's type it for
press sites username admin for example and that's type the password
we will not just for the sake of tutorial we are not in the lab we are just in
that environment so we confirm the use of week password but of course in a
production environment you need to set your password to be complex in more
context than than that we might avoid using repetitive letters use symbols
and length of 12 characters at least so here we have set password and user
so we can type here email okay and let's install the WordPress that saves
the passwords okay the WordPress has now successful being installed so let's
log into it okay and this is WordPress which is the framework in which for
example our designers can use it to design posts to media or any web pages so
it's now okay and install it so great now okay we will once the WordPress is
installed of course we need to if you remember the git we know we need to use the
git comment commit now so we are here in our directory we need to type git add
again and if we can see git status we should see here that all of these files
there is the modifications because we install the WordPress all of these files
are not committed yet so we need to commit them let's type the comment
again okay now if I show this the status now it is shown that nothing to
commit and if I try to commit it you also will give me that nothing to commit
everything is committed